<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Progress Blog</title>
    <description>-- JDE Robotics</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>ROS Navigation</title>
        <description>
          
          A post on ROS Navigation. ROS provides us with a set of software libraries and tools to simplify the task of creating complex robotics applications. ROS Navigation Stack is one such facility that ROS provides in order to carry out the task of autonomous navigation. This post talks about setting...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-03-16-ros-navigation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-03-16-ros-navigation/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Random Robotics Series 1</title>
        <description>
          
          A general post talking about random robotics developments taking/took place around the world. This is the first post of this series, so the information may be a little outdated, but will keep improving over time! Let’s suit up! Rise of Industrial Robotics At a cocktail party in 1956, Joseph Engelberger,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-03-01-random-robotics-series-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-03-01-random-robotics-series-1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Global Navigation - Part 2</title>
        <description>
          
          In the previous post, we talked about the various Global Navigation Algorithms that could be used to solve the JdeRobot exercise on Global Navigation. This post focuses on the implementation part of the algorithms, that were discussed. Let’s start with the general Breadth First Search algorithm. Once we know about...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-02-23-global-navigation-part-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-02-23-global-navigation-part-2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Global Navigation - Part 1</title>
        <description>
          
          Mobile robot navigation is an essential issue in the field of robotics. They are known for their intelligence tendencies. They also cover wide range of applications, such as in transportation, industry, and rescue robots. This post talks about the pros and cons of some algorithms for Global Navigation Exercise on...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-02-16-global-navigation-part-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-02-16-global-navigation-part-1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Competitive Robotics</title>
        <description>
          
          This post talks about Competitive Robotics, and the various competitions held around robotics. Most of the information in this post is an accumulation of all the ideas I had from my college technical fest, Advitiya held in the span of previous 3 days! Competitive Robotics Competition according to Wikipedia refers...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-02-10-competitive-robotics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-02-10-competitive-robotics/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Simple Automation</title>
        <description>
          
          Automation is the technology by which a process can be carried out with minimal human assistance. Automation can be hardware or software based. In this post we are going to talk about a software based web automation process using the python library Selenium. Far off in the future, maybe? This...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-01-26-simple-automation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-01-26-simple-automation/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coverage Algorithms - Part 2</title>
        <description>
          
          Second Part of Coverage Algortihms. This post discusses how to generate and implement a general coverage algorithm using self localization. Make sure to visit the first part to understand the basics of coverage algorithms, before reading on! Roomba on Job A Commercial Coverage Algorithm The Roomba 980, one of the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-01-11-coverage-algorithms-part-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-01-11-coverage-algorithms-part-2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Talking with Robots</title>
        <description>
          
          The heading may seem grammatically incorrect, as we can only talk to robots and not have a 2 way conversation with robots. Read on the article to find out some philosophical ideas of how we can talk with these magnificient machines! The Essence of Engineering According to Wikipedia, engineering is...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-01-04-talking-with-robots/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-01-04-talking-with-robots/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coverage Algorithms - Part 1</title>
        <description>
          
          Coverage Path Planning is an important area of research in Path Planning for robotics, which involves finding a path that passes through every reachable position in it’s environment. This post discusses a very basic Coverage Algorithm called Random Exploration, it’s implementations and some observations regarding it. Analyzing Coverage Algorithms Classification...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-12-22-coverage-algorithms-part-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-12-22-coverage-algorithms-part-1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Virtual Force Algorithms</title>
        <description>
          
          Local Navigation is an important subproblem in the field of Navigation in Robotics. It allows for the robot to break a global path into smaller parts which are effective to navigate through. This article discusses the implementation details of one such algorithm called the Virtual Force Field Algorithm. Self Driving...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-12-15-virtual-force-algorithms/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-12-15-virtual-force-algorithms/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Problem Solving 101</title>
        <description>
          
          The cons of not following a step by step approach and taking on everything all at once! Address to a previous question In one of my previous blogs, particularly this one, I referred to a question that I did not understand what exactly was JDERobot? Well, José Sir explained to...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 02:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-12-08-problem-solving-101/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-12-08-problem-solving-101/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OS Upgrade</title>
        <description>
          
          Time to update to ROS Melodic Ubuntu 18.04 Research on Navigation Being a Computer Science student, and an aspiring engineer; I really like coding and reading about different Algorithms and Data Structures. It was really great when I came to know about this particular algorithm called VFF/Virtual Force Field (Yeah,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-12-02-os-upgrade/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-12-02-os-upgrade/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Way to EDITH</title>
        <description>
          
          Many curious questions left at the end of this week. What is JDERobot exactly? How exactly to use the ICE Framework? Where is it being used in JDERobot? The COOL part! After merging of the pull request, I wanted to solve some other exercise, follow_road. Seeing unknown terms like mavros...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-11-23-way-to-edith/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-11-23-way-to-edith/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dark GIFs</title>
        <description>
          
          Tweaking the launch files to import the required models and; updating and organizing the follow_line exercise webpage, were the main tasks of this week. The light part of this week As discussed with José Sir, I am to update the webpage of the follow_line exercise. The webpage was missing Theory,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 05:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019-11-17-dark-gifs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019-11-17-dark-gifs/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
